Guide to the Stanford Museum Collection
Stanford University Library
- Museum objects
  - Buttons (all different, with cartoons or graphics), ARCH-AM-2008-013 (Box 1)
    013.1 Robotics 013.2 Architecture 013.3 Compilers 013.4 CAD 013.5 Office Systems 013.6 Algorithms 013.7 Human Interfaces 013.8 Numerical Analysis 013.9 Verification 013.10 Human Interfaces 013.11 Networks 013.12 Expert Systems 013.13 Distributed Systems 013.14 Natural Languages 013.15 Programming Environments013.16 Computer Graphics 013.17 Theory 013.18 VLSI 013.19 Programming Languages 013.20 Reliability
  - Buttons and a pin from alumni reunions, ARCH-AM-2001-33 (Box 1)
    33.1 Stanford '41 / '91 Half Century Club 33.2 Stanford Half Century Club 1926 / 1976 33.3 Stanford Half Century Club '43 [1993] 33.4 Stanford Class Reunion 1988 33.5 Stanford 1940-1990 Fiftieth [lapel pin]
  - Buttons and badges (Stanford athletics) mounted in two albums (56 items total), ARCH-AM-1985-07 (Box 1)
  - Buttons from football games, ARCH-AM-2001-34 (Box 1)
    34.1 Big Game Bear Hunt 34.2 Stanford vs. Notre Dame 10/3/92 34.3 Stanford @ Notre Dame October 1, 1988
  - Buttons issued for the 1983 visit of Queen Elizabeth on campus - "Stanford University 1983 Queen Elizabeth" - attached to card from President and Mrs. Donald Kenndy, with message "A memento of the Queen's Visit. Jeanne and Don" (3 copies), ARCH-AM-2008-015 (Box 1)
  - Buttons metal. white bkg with '30 in red letters. 9cm diam. pin on back (two identical buttons), ARCH-AM-1980-18 (Box 1)
  - Buttons, celebrating opening of bookstore expansion, summer 1978 (4); Stanford Christmas faire (2), ARCH-AM-1979-06 (Box 1)
    79-06.1 and .2 I Read Books for the Stanford Bookstore 79-06.3 Welcome to the Stanford Bookstore 79-06.4 Join Our Book Club 25% off bestsellers 79-96.5 and .6 Stanford Christmas Faire
  - Buttons, mostly Indian theme, ca. 1950s, ARCH-AM-2003-004 (Box 1)
    004.1 lil injun pointing to himself 004.2 lil injun in football uniform 004.3 indian with axe leaning on Cal bear 004.4 indian with axe sitting on Cal bear 004.5 lil injun head superimposed over "S" 004.6 "Hitch up to the Wiggin Wagon" 004.7 indian head with feather headdress 004.8 "BEAT UCLA" 004.9 "BEAT CAL"
  - Buttons: "Summer Job Fair" (yellow and blue); "Study at TMU" black and yellow. n.d., ARCH-AM-1984-13 (Box 1)
  - Buttons: Beat Cal 1977 and Spring Fling 1979, ARCH-AM-2004-009 (Box 1)
    009.1 BEAT CAL BIG GAME '77; 009.2 Spring Fling '79
  - Buttons: metal, red bkg, white letters, class of '30, 40th reunion, Stanford. (Denny Driggs, 10cm, diam., pin on back). two= identical, ARCH-AM-1980-19 (Box 1)
  - Buttons. Metal pin-on buttons for holidays and other events. 1978, 1982, 1983., ARCH-AM-1984-02 (Box 1)
    1984-02.1 Harvest October 1 1984-02.2 Coffee House 2 years and growing Anniversary '82 1984-02.3 Stanford Christmas Faire Dec. 4-6 [1983?] 1984-02.4 Staff Stanford Christmas Faire [1983?] 1984-02.5 Beat Cal Big Game '78 [image of Gryphon?] 1984-02.6 Beat Cal Big Game '78 [axe head image]
  - C.P. Jupiter / U.P. 119 Centennial Locomotive Set / The Golden Spike - 0 scale models of 2 locomotives that met at Promontory, Utah; in own large wooden box.[Originally given to Cantor Center on Sept. 4, 2001, which sent it to the Archives.], ARCH-AM-2001-30 (Box 1)
  - Calendar for 1883 "With Best Wishes for Many Happy Returns of the Day" - pasted on board with fringe and pink braid trim, ARCH-AM-2004-024 (Box 1)
  - Calligraphy, about University Archives. frame 58-45cm, image 51x33cm., ARCH-AM-2000-329 (Box 1)
  - Calligraphy, re Bender Room. 51 x 32 cm.REMOVED AND CLASSED AS PRINT 306, ARCH-AM-2000-324 (Box 1)
  - Candle Stick label: 5.5 diam. x 3 cm hi. Belonged to President Madison, for melting sealing wax., ARCH-AM-2000-251 (Box 1)
  - cane with metal cap: "Stanford '95", ARCH-AM-1995-23 (Box 1)
  - Cane, with silver plates engraved with yearly editorial staff of the Chapparal (192000-1925), ARCH-AM-2000-007 (Box 1)
  - Canvas bag. Front: STANFORD UNIVERSITY with square containing "S", the Tree, the seal, and "U". Back: Compliments of Stanford Bookstore. Red ink on natural canvas, ARCH-AM-2002-37 (Box 1)
  - Cap and Gown pins (3 of same design but from different times) - gold with black enamel in shape of mortar board cap, ARCH-AM-2008-020 (Box 1)
    2008-020.1 "Hazel Levery '07" on back 2008-020.2 blank on reverse 2008-020.3 initials E. J. on back
  - Cap, beanie, red., ARCH-AM-2000-171 (Box 1)
  - Cap: Stanford Class of '80 Five Year Reunion, ARCH-AM-2006-020 (Box 1)
  - Card file (3x5) used by Elliott for notes on Stanford History, ARCH-AM-1995-18 (Box 1)
  - Card. 9x5 cm. "I have worked on class of 1918 Bonfire.", ARCH-AM-2000-195 (Box 1)
  - Cardboard accompanying the above drawings. "Zoology Dept. Painted cloth materials.", ARCH-AM-2000-130.27 (Box 1)
  - Carpet Board: Lil Injun figures, with Stanford spelled out on their backs, ARCH-AM-1994-11 (Box 1)
  - Case for razors., ARCH-AM-2000-151.3 (Box 1)
  - Catalog. "Psychological and Physiological Apparatus and Supplies." 1930, ARCH-AM-2000-107.1 (Box 1)
  - Cement block memorial plaque: "In Memory of Alan Brown 1956-1979". Removed due to landscape construction [location not specified]., ARCH-AM-2005-014 (Box 1)
  - Cement tiles from Hanna House, ARCH-AM-2005-026 (Box 1)
  - Cent. Award presented to Dept. of Special Collections: sandstone rocks and replica of trowel, ARCH-AM-1991-097 (Box 1)
  - Centennial Banner flown on space shuttle Columbia, 1990, ARCH-AM-1994-02 (Box 1)
  - Centennial Banners (large)., ARCH-AM-1991-099 (Box 1)
    1991-099.1 Red white nylon "Stanford 100 Years" with stylized tree1991-099.2 Red nylon with unrecognized design element 1991-099.3 Red white nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.4 Red white nylon with stylized palm trees 1991-099.5-7 White beige with red Centennial logo [.6 and .7 still in unopened plastic bags] 1991-099.8-9 Turquoise nylon with stylized palm trees 1991-099.10 Turquoise nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.11 Red nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.12 Red nylon with abstract figures 1991-099.13 White beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.14 White beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.15 White beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.16 White beige possibly with Stanford 100 [too large] 1991-099.17 Red nylon with stylized design of Quad column head 1991-099.18 Beige with Centennial logo 1991-099.19 Red with abstract figures ? 1991-099.20 [Beige, still in plastic bag] 1991-099.21 [Beige, still in plastic bag] 1991-099.22 [overlarge red nylon - more than one, but too large to unfold]
  - Centennial Medallions (silver and bronze), ARCH-AM-1994-06 (Box 1)
  - Centennial memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1995-05 (Box 1)
    1. Cent. commencement pin, 1991 2. Cent. 100th class pin, 1991 3. Centennial pin 4. T-shirt: Centennial Finale Weekend, 1991
  - Centennial memorabilia - cup and pin, ARCH-AM-1992-12 (Box 1)
    Plastic cup - Parents' Weekend and Founders Day 1991 (2) Pin - "Preparing for the Next 100 Years"
  - Ceramic box in the shape of the Stanford house in Sacramento, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-029 (Box 1)
  - Ceramic Tile with tinted picture of Leland Jr. 24x16x.5 cm, tinted photo, head and shoulders., ARCH-AM-2000-248 (Box 1)
  - Ceremonial sword of T. Hopkins, with scabard., ARCH-AM-2001-18 (Box 1)
  - Certificate for Japanese Student Assoc. 1914, 51x53 cm. black frame with glass. From State of California., ARCH-AM-2000-113 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, Framed in glass. 29X41 cm. Wm H. Bonsall, Admission to California State Bar, 1938, ARCH-AM-2000-183 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, framed with glass. 25X31 cm. W.H.Bonsall, US District Court, qualifies as attorney., ARCH-AM-2000-182 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, framed; gives Timothy Hopkins life privileges to Levi Cooper Lane. Library of Med. Surgery; frame 41x49, image 35x42 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-279 (Box 1)
  - Certificate, Framed. 40X29 cm. Inscribes Leland Stanford's name on immortals of florence nightingale Inst., ARCH-AM-2000-180 (Box 1)
  - Certificate; framed, glass; Charter of Phi Beta Kappa; Sept. 1904. Stanford University. 52x34 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-290 (Box 1)
  - Champagne bottle: Stanford / Governor's Cuvee / Champagne of California (Weibel Vineyards), ARCH-AM-2000-005 (Box 1)
  - Champagne bottle: Stanford Governors Cuvee by Leland Stanford Winery Mission San Jose, Calif., ARCH-AM-1984-51 (Box 1)
  - Champagne flutes from Viennese Ball 2000 and 2001, ARCH-AM-2007-018 (Box 1)
    2007-018.1 2000 Ball; 2007-018.2 2001 Ball
  - Champagne glass, 1968, "Stanford Class of 1918 Golden Anniversary", ARCH-AM-1978-08 (Box 1)
  - Charter of Society of Sigma Xi, LSJU chapter, 1901, ARCH-AM-1979-01 (Box 1)
  - Cigar box "La Flor Stanford" with illustrations on inside lid of Leland Stanford, state capital, and stock farm, ARCH-AM-1992-09 (Box 1)
  - Circle of Friends award to Stanford University from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 2003. Lucite shape with etched letters. 9 in. high, 3.5 in. wide., ARCH-AM-2006-029 (Box 1)
  - Class hat, 1906; red beanie (sophomore ?), ARCH-AM-2000-048 (Box 1)
  - Class hat, 1913; pith helmet, ARCH-AM-2000-049 (Box 1)
  - Cloth diagrams of flowers; used for botany class instruction. 25 pieces, ARCH-AM-2000-032 (Box 1)
  - Clothing-outerwear, Tshirt-- 1981 white cotton (anvil brand) with Leland Jr. portrait on front; L. Jr. "letter" and signature on back., ARCH-AM-1982-01 (Box 1)
  - Coaster with image of Memorial Church, Memorial Arch, and hills in background., ARCH-AM-2000-025 (Box 1)
  - Collage of photographs, university seal, and American flag that were flown aboard the Space Shuttle Atlantis, January 1997; signed by Jeff Wisoff, U. S. Astronaut. Originally given to Bill Stone, president of SAA, ARCH-AM-2001-10 (Box 1)
  - Collection of political pins and buttons of Miss Elizabeth Nash. In square box., ARCH-AM-2000-215 (Box 1)
    2000-215.1 American flag pin, 1.3x1cm 2000-215.2 Medal, 3.5cm diam. Richelieu etc. 2000-215.3 Medal, 2cm diam. from S.S. Beaver 2000-215.4 Medal, 5cm diam. "Divisao de Geologia." 2000-215.5 Button-pin, 2cm "Votes for Women." 2000-215.6 Button-pin, 2cm Grant Photo 2000-215.7 Button-pin, 6cm "Barclay President" 2000-215.8 Button-pin, 6cm Humanity Legion aid to China 2000-215.9 Button-pin, 2cm. Liberty, Equality, etc. 2000-215.10 Button-pin, 2.5cm "Wilkie for President" 2000-215.11 Button-pin, 5.5cm leather - McGovern 2000-215.12 Button-pin, 3cm, McGovern-Shriver 2000-215.13 Button-pin, 3cm "McGovern" 2000-215.14 Button-pin, 3cm, Nixon now more then, etc. 2000-215.15 Button-pin, 3cm diam., "Nixon Now" 2000-215.16 Button-pin, 5cm, ""Pres. Nixon no more... etc. 2000-215.17 Button-pin, 2.5cm, Nixon, gold on black 2000-215.18 Button-pin, 2.5cm, "I like Ike" 2000-215.19 Button with ribbons - frosty sons of thunder, Somerset County Pa.
  - Commemmorative dinner plate with images of Hoover Tower, inner quad, east gateway, Memorial Church, outer quad, and stadium, ARCH-AM-2000-004 (Box 1)
  - Commemorative souvenirs collected by the Centennial office from other institutions' anniversary events, ARCH-AM-1991-101 (Box 1)
    1991-101.1 Pennant from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.2 Pennant from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.3 Battery operated sparkler from US Olympic Festival '90 1991-101.4 Label pin US Olympic Festival '90 [flag shape] 1991-101.5 Label pin US Olympic Festival '90 [oval] 1991-101.6 Button from 350th Harvard anniversary
  - Community Day Stanford Ultimate Frisbee Team - frisbee [no date on it], ARCH-AM-2006-019 (Box 1)
  - Community Day Stanford Ultimate Frisbee Team - frisbee, ca. 2003, ARCH-AM-2004-030 (Box 1)
  - computer mousepads from SunNet given out at conference. (earth and spacestation Mir on black background) - 6 items, ARCH-AM-1999-005 (Box 1)
  - Concrete sample "Quad Column Approved Sample 10-00-3". Curved piece showing outside ridges. ca. 2000, ARCH-AM-2006-036 (Box 1)
  - Construction materials, ca. 2001, ARCH-AM-2002-05 (Box 1)
    2002-05.1 replacement material for ceiling 2002-05.2 frame (possibly original) for soffitt light fixtures in Hobby House [boxed with AM 2002-03] 2002-05.3 sample of original concrete floor 2002-05.4 core sample from terrace
  - Copper plated printing block of image of earthquake-damaged 1900 library; framed, ARCH-AM-2002-12 (Box 1)
  - Corn-cob pipe used in Encina smokers, ARCH-AM-2004-015 (Box 1)
  - Costumes (vests and blouses - 6 items), ARCH-AM-2008-017 (Box 1)
  - Cup, metal. 9cm high. Souvenier of Stanford University, Palo Alto tree, Mem. Arch, Quad, and Chapel entrance., ARCH-AM-2000-192 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: D.S. Jordan, ARCH-AM-2000-067 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: J. L. Stanford, ARCH-AM-2000-068 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Leland St., Jr., ARCH-AM-2000-070 (Box 1)
  - Death Mask: Leland Stanford, ARCH-AM-2000-069 (Box 1)
  - Decal of L'il Injun face, ca. 1965, ARCH-AM-2006-005 (Box 1)
  - Decal: Stanford University with "S" and tree placed between, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-017 (Box 1)
  - Delta Tau Delta paddleboard and letter from Fred Glover, names of Delt initiates carved on it., ARCH-AM-1984-56 (Box 1)
  - demi-tasse cup and saucer, c. 1895, painted scene "North Arcade, St. Unive., Ca.", ARCH-AM-1980-25 (Box 1)
  - Demitasse cup belonging to Jessie K. Jordan, ARCH-AM-1979-07 (Box 1)
  - Denim work shirt with SULAIR HighWire Press Stanford University Press embroidered on left front, along with symbol for each., ARCH-AM-2007-012 (Box 1)
  - Die, used for Tree Stamp in 1969 for Libraries., ARCH-AM-2000-218 (Box 1)
  - Die; 12x3x1 cm. Made by Mesabi Iron Co. S.F., ARCH-AM-2000-237 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, 7x5x2, The Barbara Jordon Library of Birds., ARCH-AM-2000-236 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, ExLibris, Kate Felton Elkins with scenic picture., ARCH-AM-2000-234 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, Leland Stanford University Library, presented by Timothy Welton Stanford. 4x6x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-235 (Box 1)
  - Die; Bookplate, Stanford Univ. Library. 8x5x2 cm. Journalism Library., ARCH-AM-2000-232 (Box 1)
  - Die; David Starr Jordan's Book Plate., ARCH-AM-2000-252 (Box 1)
  - Die; Group of men under Quad Arch. 15x11x2 cm. (Geology), ARCH-AM-2000-224 (Box 1)
  - Die; Insurance Policy from Pacific Mutual on Life of Leland Stanford. 15x10x2., ARCH-AM-2000-247 (Box 1)
  - Die; John Almack Memorial Collection. 11x8 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-230 (Box 1)
  - Die; Labelled Charles Stanford. 13x10x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-226 (Box 1)
  - Die; Picture of man. 6x9x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-220 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait Signature of J.C. Branner., ARCH-AM-2000-246 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of a man. 8x6x2., ARCH-AM-2000-229 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of man, 9x15x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-222 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of Man; 13x10x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-227 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of Man; 16x11cm., ARCH-AM-2000-225 (Box 1)
  - Die; Portrait of man. 6x9x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-221 (Box 1)
  - Die; Stanford Church. 11x16x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-223 (Box 1)
  - Die; Stanford University Library bookplate; 9x6x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-231 (Box 1)
  - Die: Stanford Path at Lagunita. 9x12x2 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-228 (Box 1)
  - Diploma, black frame with glass; 84x108 cm., awarded to David Starr Jordan by Internat. Fisheries Exhibition., ARCH-AM-2000-089 (Box 1)
  - Diploma, Harvard University. For Wm Bonsall. 35X39 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-184 (Box 1)
  - Doll, Stanford Football Player. 14cm high, in red sweater with block "S". [sticker on bottom - "Varsity Vic"; copyright Bud Pione carved on back of figure], ARCH-AM-2000-194 (Box 1)
  - Donald Tresidder memorabilia, ARCH-AM-1984-58 (Box 1)
    1. academic hood belonging to Pres. Donald Tresidder, purple and blue velvet 2. academic hood belonging to Pres. Donald Tresidder, green and red velvet 3. Pennant ""Stanford"" maroon
  - Double sleigh bed previously owned by Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur (from the Dunn-Bacon house), ARCH-AM-1998-020 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin, c.1898 61X89 cm. Shasta daisy in color on muslin., ARCH-AM-2000-130.04 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 109X89 Green Crayon drawing. Hyrid poppy leaves, Burbank., ARCH-AM-2000-130.02 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 1914. 91X91 cm. Ink drawing. Tall man and short man standing by yardstick. From J.of Heredity vol 5. no.11, Nov.1914., ARCH-AM-2000-130.23 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 64X107 cm. Diagrams of Okimonas Termo, Euglena Viridis, Haematococcus Pandorina., ARCH-AM-2000-130.25 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 66X94 cm. Used for class instruction; Physiological Morphology, 1898. Black Ink. Sea Urchin, extra ovates., ARCH-AM-2000-130.01 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 86X61 cm. Subject; artificial selection. Hybrid walnut; cross between Japanese English walnut., ARCH-AM-2000-130.24 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 86X91 cm. Brown crayon on white. Diagram of flower showing pollination (To illustrate method of cross pollination.), ARCH-AM-2000-130.11 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 89X107 cm. Leaves from second generation seedlings of walnut., ARCH-AM-2000-130.13 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X104 cm. Burbank scarlet poppy hybrid. Colored Crayon., ARCH-AM-2000-130.14 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X107 cm. c.1898. Hybridology. Wild stoneless plum and french prune., ARCH-AM-2000-130.15 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X114 cm. Artificial selection: Variation in poppy capsules., ARCH-AM-2000-130.21 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. 91X114cm. Two pedelled hybrid seedling lily. Color-artificial selection., ARCH-AM-2000-130.07 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X130 cm. c.1898. Lecture; Wheat Breeding. Artificial selection., ARCH-AM-2000-130.12 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 91X86 cm. First fixed primus blackberry artifically produced., ARCH-AM-2000-130.22 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. 97X91 cm. Variation on Hybridization. Half Sour-half sweet apple and half green yellow- half red. "A most remarkable result.", ARCH-AM-2000-130.26 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. c. 1898. 63X104 cm. Drawings of Amoeba, Chondriodema difforme Dipflugia., ARCH-AM-2000-130.16 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. c.1898, 89X61 cm. Artificial selection- original and improved beach plum., ARCH-AM-2000-130.03 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. c.1898. 104X91 cm. The first double shasta daisy. Curious forms among asta daisey seedlings., ARCH-AM-2000-130.05 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. c.1898. 48X91 cm. Thallus and fruit of spineless cactus., ARCH-AM-2000-130.17 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. c.1898. 91X117 cm. Seven types of Canaries. Drawn from Romanes. Darwin after Darwin., ARCH-AM-2000-130.08 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. c.1898. 91X124. Leaves from a strawberry-rasberry hybrid., ARCH-AM-2000-130.18 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. c.1898. 91X32 cm. Sample leaves of common garden dahlia. (Showing variation within species when under cultivation.), ARCH-AM-2000-130.10 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. c.1898. 91X71. Subj. natural selection; Wild Boar and modern pig. Ink drawing., ARCH-AM-2000-130.20 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on muslin. c.1898. 91X79 cm. Lecture; Instinct Reason; Structure involving simple reflex; spinal cord, etc., ARCH-AM-2000-130.19 (Box 1)
  - Drawing on Muslin. c.1907 91X271 cm. Black ink drawing on Muslin. Century Magazine, 1907. Man examining two long Rooster tails., ARCH-AM-2000-130.06 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed of Memorial Library. frame 65x79cm, image 48x63 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-318 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed of Memorial Library. Signed Samuel Newsome (same as 2000-318). frame 81x69, image 47x59 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-319 (Box 1)
  - Drawing, Architectural, framed, of Memorial Library. Signed Samuel Newsome (same as 2000-318). frame 61 x 113, image 44x96 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-323 (Box 1)
  - Drawings, Architectural, Tinted. Leland Stanford Jr. Univ. Shepley, Rutan, Coolidge. frame 119x48, ARCH-AM-2000-327 (Box 1)
  - Drums used by the Band - 2 kettle drums and 1 snare drum; one kettle drum has torn drumhead; 6 drum sticks (one is brush-type); canvas case for snare drum, ARCH-AM-2007-020 (Box 1)
    2007-020.1 kettle drum (intact) 2007-020.2 kettle drum (torn head 2007-020.3 snare drum 2007-020.4 case 2007-020.5 sticks
  - Duplicate image of Donald Kennedy's presidential portrait, ARCH-AM-2005-019 (Box 1)
  - El Tigre Club paddle, c. 1934, ARCH-AM-1980-26 (Box 1)
  - Embosser for defunct University Seal, ARCH-AM-2004-005 (Box 1)
  - Embosser for Vina Agency, ARCH-AM-2008-001 (Box 1)
  - Embosser of the Delta Upsilon Alumni Association (see accn 1997-192 for records), ARCH-AM-1997-016 (Box 1)
  - embosser with Trustees' seal [now defunct as official seal]: "Seal of the Leland Stanford Junior University 1885" in outer circle, image of tree in the center with "Semper Virens", ARCH-AM-2005-013 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered Indian Head used as model for blankets; designed by A. Phimister Proctor for Dr. Tom Williams, ARCH-AM-1978-11 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered mourning scenes by Mary Nancy Kellogg ca. 1840: in hinged wood box (includes typed note re. people represented), ARCH-AM-1995-10 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered patch, SU seal (tree, Leland Stanford Junior University, organized 1891)., ARCH-AM-1980-13 (Box 1)
  - Embroidered satin bag (once contained Jane L. Stanford's opera glasses), ARCH-AM-2000-027 (Box 1)
  - Enameled Pin: NCAA Women's Final Four San Antonio 2002, ARCH-AM-2008-012 (Box 1)
  - Engraving of L. Stanford portrait with his signature, for printing purposes [used as frontispiece in George T. Clark's biography of LS]. Mounted on red velvet and framed, ARCH-AM-2000-043 (Box 1)
  - Ephemera from men's final 4: pins, signs, pennant, cups., ARCH-AM-1998-017 (Box 1)
    98-017.1 pin "FINAL FOUR" with emblems of 4 schools 98-017.2 pin "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR STANFORD UTAH KENTUCKY NORTH CAROLINA" 98-017.3 pennant: Stanford 1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR 98-017.4 and .5 plastic cup "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR ALAMODOME" 98-017.6 and .7 plastic cup "1998 NCAA FINAL FOUR SAN ANTONIO" 98-017.8 and .9 two-sided sign: JUST DO IT CARDINAL; JUST DO IT STANFORD
  - Etching, framed, glass, Abeside, Memorial Church. frame 46x34 cm, image 19x14 cm. [MOVED TO PRINT COLLECTION 2/2006], ARCH-AM-2000-273 (Box 1)
  - Etching; framed, glass, Title page of eight etchings by Louis Orr. frame 46x34 cm, image 19x14 cm. [MOVED TO PRINT COLLECTION 2/2006], ARCH-AM-2000-272 (Box 1)
  - Etching; framed, glass; Old Union and Fountain, signed Louis Orr. frame 47x35 cm, image 21x17 cm., ARCH-AM-2000-301 (Box 1)
  - Examples of stone work from the old Encina Gym (razed in 2004): cap stone, 2 squares, example of cast stone, ARCH-AM-2004-010 (Box 1)
  - Fallfest: two red caps, one button (white and blue), 1983., ARCH-AM-1984-12 (Box 1)
  - Fan (Palo Alto tree on red background) from 1999 Convocation, with text of "Hail, Stanford, Hail" and program (2), ARCH-AM-1999-025 (Box 1)
  - fan from 110th Opening Convocation with program and text of "Hail, Stanford, Hail" on one side and image on the other (5 items), ARCH-AM-2000-011 (Box 1)
  - Fan from 117th Convocation; on reverse: program order, text of Hail, Stanford, Hail. (2 items - round paper on wooden handle), ARCH-AM-2008-008 (Box 1)
  - Felt applique in shape of an Indian head with embroidery, undated; ARCH-AM-2009-019 (Box 1)
  - Felt banners: 1) Palo Alto Military Academy, 2) Rose Bowl - Stanford, 3) Stanford (with Indian head), ARCH-AM-1991-095 (Box 1)
  - Felt hat: red white reversible with diamond shape applique on top, ARCH-AM-1991-092 (Box 1)
  - felt pennant "Stanford" with tree over the "S" - red letters on white felt., ARCH-AM-1995-34 (Box 1)
  - Fencing Jacke; 79X41cm. White padded shoulders, laces up the front., ARCH-AM-2000-131 (Box 1)
  - Fencing jacket of R H. Hull and straw sombrero (reputed to be a senior sombrero from SU class earlier than 1928), ARCH-AM-2006-007 (Box 1)
    2006-007.1 jacket "SU" in red felt on left sleeve 2006-007.2 hat, dark brown woven straw, 19" in diameter